Geoffrey Hunter, Ph.D.

+ 1 416 294 7509 | LinkedIn Profile | GH@WidgetsAndDigits.ca

SUMMARY

I have 9 years of experience in a research environment and 5 additional years of experience bridging technical and business teams around data science initiatives spanning the Marketing, Financial, Life Science industries. In this capacity, I advise business executives and senior leadership to facilitate an understanding of AI and lead the organization's data strategy. I also lead and mentor technical data science teams into nimble, end-to-end, product-focused teams.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Manager, Data Science Uberflip

08/2018 - Present

Uberflip is creating a platform for content marketers to discover, distribute, and personalize content. I am championing the company's data strategy and mentor the cross-functional team to deliver on this strategy

- Conduct discovery and ideation sessions with the executives and senior leadership to identify and qualify data science solutions and products
- Provide hands-on execution in the design and development of data pipelines, API's, BI
 dashboards, and machine learning solutions to enhance the ROI of Uberflip for customers and
 answer internal business problems around product adoption and maturity, optimizing sales
 engagement strategies, and identifying strategies to limit customer churn
- Mentor and grow a close, highly skilled team of data scientists, data engineers, UX engineers, and analysts to solution priority business needs

Technologies: Python, Snowflake, Looker, Matillion, (Py)Spark, AWS, GitLab, SQL Problems: Time series forecasting, customer segmentation, recommender systems, topic modelling

Advisor 08/2018 - Present

Toronto Machine Learning Summit (TMLS)

The TMLS holds an annual AI conference appealing to over 800 attendees, 100 startups, and stakeholders from across the industry. I advise the organizing committee with strategic support on how to grow the appeal of the conference and assess speaking proposals

Head of Data Science 05/2017 - 05/2018 TribalScale

TribalScale is a rapidly growing, global consulting company that specializes in enterprise digital innovation. I spearheaded the creation of their new data science offering.

- Conceptualized and drove the vision and go-to-market strategy for the data science practice in collaboration with the executive, sales, and marketing teams
- Promoted and articulated the offerings, benefits, and capabilities of the data science practice in proposals and in internal and client-facing presentations
- Product strategist and solutions architect for data science use cases such as search engines, recommender systems, chatbots, route navigation, preference-based planning solutions, and variable pricing models

Technologies: Python, Google Cloud Platform Problems: Generalized assignment problem

Data Scientist 02/2016 - 05/2017

Deloitte Canada

Deloitte is one of the "Big 4" management consulting firms. I was a subject matter expert in data science and helped with the strategic planning, development, and implementation of medium-to-large machine learning solutions for enterprises.

- Lead Python developer on an agile scrum team of up to ten developers creating data ingestion solution to enable data science teams to gather data from across the enterprise for analytics work at a major
- Canadian financial institution Lead data scientist that developed an analytics solution for a consortium of five government agencies to identify tax non-compliant businesses and helped shape open data legislation in Canada
- Data science strategist that advised a not-for-profit sector client on ways to leverage data to gain a 360 degree view of donors, reduce donor churn, and enhance their donor engagement strategy

Technologies: Python, R, SQL, Cloudera, Tableau, Github, Subversion

Problems: Fraud / anomaly detection, topic modelling, customer segmentation, chatbots

Owner & Consultant 09/2015 – 02/2016 Widgets and Digits

Widgets and Digits provides startup companies with data science advisory and technical experience to drive product development and customer engagement

 Designed an algorithm to automatically classify nocturnal seizures using accelerometer data from smartwatches Provided a medical diagnostics company with a data strategy on how better to streamline their data capture and automate reporting

Technologies: Python, SQL, Github

Problems: Anomaly detection, time series analysis

Postdoctoral Fellow 05/2014 – 02/2016

Ontario Institute for Cancer Research

Technologies: C, R, Perl, Subversion

Problems: Hierarchical clustering, elastic lasso, PCA, random forest, Restricted Boltzmann machine, survival models

EDUCATION

| University of Utah Ph.D., Applied Mathematics | 2006 – 2013 |
|--|-------------|
| University of Utah M.S., Applied Mathematics | 2004 – 2006 |
| University of Waterloo B.Math, Applied Mathematics | 1999 – 2004 |

| Coursera Deep Learning Specialization | In Progress |
|---|-------------|
| AWS Cloud Practitioner | 2019 |
| Coursera Data Engineering Specialization on Google Cloud Platform | 2017 |